We've discussed the diverse applications of Reinforcement Learning.
我们讨论了强化学习的各种应用
Each has a defining agent and environment,
每个应用都有一个智能体和环境
and each agent has a goal.
每个智能体都有一个目标
Ranging from a car learning to drive itself to an agent learning to play Atari games.
从学习无人驾驶的汽车到学习玩 Atari 游戏的智能体
It's truly amazing that all of
很令人震惊的是
these very different goals can be addressed with the same theoretical framework.
所有这些完全不同的目标可以通过相同的理论框架来实现
So far, we've made sense of the idea of reward from
到目前为止 我们通过小狗与主人互动
the perspective of a puppy that interacts with its owner.
了解了奖励这一概念
In this case, the state did in the timestep was
在此情形中 任何时间步的状态是
the command that the owner communicated to the puppy,
主人向小狗发出的指令
the action was the puppy's response,
动作是小狗的响应
and the reward was just the number of treats.
奖励是骨头奖赏次数
And like a good Reinforcement Learning Agent,
和良好的强化学习智能体一样
the puppy seeks to maximize that reward.
小狗的目标是最大化这种奖赏
In this case, the idea of reward comes naturally.
在这种情形下 奖励这一概念很自然
And it lines up well with the way we think about teaching a puppy.
与我们训练小狗的思维很一致
But in fact, the Reinforcement Learning Framework has any and
但实际上 强化学习框架是指让所有智能体
all agents formulate their goals in terms of maximizing expected cumulative reward.
制定最大化期望累积奖励这一目标
But what could reward mean in the context of something like a robot learning to walk?
对于学习如何行走的机器人来说 奖励是什么意思呢？
Maybe we could think of the environment as a type of trainer that
我们可以将这种环境看做训练员观察机器人的动作
watches the robots movements and rewards it for having good walking form.
并在行走姿势正确时奖励机器人
But then the reward that it gives has the
但是这种奖励可能会非常具有主观性
potential to be highly subjective and not scientific at all.
根本没有科学定义
I mean, what makes a walk good?
什么样的行走姿势是好的姿势？
And what makes it bad?
什么样的又是坏的姿势？
And how do we address this?
如何处理此问题？
In general, how do we specify reward to
通常 如何指定奖励
describe any of a number of potential goals that our agents could have?
以便描述智能体可能会具有的任何潜在目标数量？
Well before we answer this question,
在回答此问题之前
let's take one step back.
我们先来了解另一个知识
It's important to note that the word "Reinforcement" and
要注意的是 “强化”和“强化学习”
"Reinforcement Learning" is a term originally from behavioral science.
这两个术语本身来自行为科学
It refers to a stimulus that's delivered immediately after
是指在行为之后立即发生的刺激
behavior to make the behavior more likely to occur in the future.
使该行为在未来更有可能发生
The fact that this name is borrowed is no coincidence.
采用这一名称并非偶然
In fact, it's an important to defining hypothesis and
实际上 在强化学习中 有一个重要的定义假设
reinforcement learning that we can always formulate an agents goal,
即智能体的目标始终可以描述为
along the lines of maximizing expected cumulative reward.
最大化期望累积奖励
And we call this hypothesis, the "Reward Hypothesis".
我们将这种假设称之为奖励假设
If this still seems weird or uncomfortable to you, you are not alone.
如果你依然不太理解 不用担心 并不是只有你一个人有这种想法
But allow me to convince you in the next video.
我将在下个视频中详细讲解